## Regi Kusumaatmadja

Amsterdam, 1082 MS, The Netherlands (+31)-6-33-204-172 or r.kusumaatmadja@tinbergen.nl https://id.linkedin.com/in/regikusumaatmadja

## SHORT PROFILE

Regi is currently pursuing his graduate study (MPhil/Ph.D. Track) at Tinbergen Institute, The Netherlands. Regi is a former researcher at LPEM FEB UI, where he was mainly responsible for supervising data management and assisting (Co)Project Investigators in analysis and writing. He has worked with a broad spectrum of decision-makers from the government agencies, private corporate, and non-profit organizations.

## **EDUCATION**

MPhil/PhD Track, Economics

Aug 2019 - now

Tinbergen Institute, Amsterdam & Rotterdam, The Netherlands

MSc, Economics

Aug 2017 - July 2018

Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands

GPA: 8.1/10, Cum Laude

Thesis: Trade and wage-setting power: Evidence from China's accession to WTO

BSc, Physics

Aug 2012 - Aug 2016

Universitas Indonesia, Depok, Indonesia,

GPA: 3.75/4.00, *Cum Laude*,  $1^{st}$  rank in the department,  $2^{nd}$  rank in the faculty Concentration: Theoretical and Computational Condensed Matter Physics

## **EXPERIENCE**

Research and Teaching Assistant

Sept 2020 - Present

Department of Economics & Department of Spatial Economics - VU Amsterdam

- RA for Dr. Sabien Dobbelaere and Prof. Eric Bartelsman at Dept. Economics for the project "Firm Innovation and Firm Dynamics" at Department of Economics - VU
- TA of MSc Spatial Economics programme at Department of Spatial Economics
   VU (under Prof. Hans Koster and Prof. Jos van Ommeren)

Researcher Aug 2018 - Nov 2019

Institute for Economic and Social Research (LPEM FEB-UI)

- Assisting Investigator (PI: M. Halley Yudhistira) in analysis and writing, and supervising data management for two research projects: "Evaluating the impact of Asian Games and WB-IMF on traffic congestion" (funded by The Indonesian Ministry of National Development (Bappenas) and Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade (DFAT), The Australian Government)
- Assissting Co-Investigator (Co PI: T. Dartanto) in analysis and writing, and supervising data management for a research project: "Estimating the demand for social infrastructures in Asia" (joint with and funded by Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA))
- Assisting Investigator (PI: C. Nuryakin) in analysis and writing, and supervising data management for a research project: "Airlines Industry Liberalization in Indonesia" (funded by a private entity)

Teaching Assistant Aug 2018 - July 2019

Graduate School of Economics - Universitas Indonesia

• Macroeconomic Theory I: Basics of the DSGE model (RBC and NK)

• Macroeconomic Theory II: Modeling the economic growth (Solow and RCK)

Graduate School of Public Policy - Universitas Indonesia Feb 2019 - June 2019

• Applied Econometrics: OLS, Instrumental variables, Panel data models

AWARDS AND Awardee, Tinbergen Institute Full Scholarship, 2019 - now

Awardee, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam Fellowship Programme (VUFP), 2017

**FELLOWSHIPS** Awardee, Holland Scholarship Programme (HSP), 2017

Best Graduate, Department of Physics, Universitas Indonesia, 2016

Top 1 (one) Percent, Faculty of Mathematics and Natural Sciences, Universitas In-

donesia, 2016

Oral Presenter at International Symposium of Current Progress on Functional Mate-

rials (ISCPFM), 2016

Awardee, XL-Axiata Future Leaders (XLFL) Scholarship, 2014-2016

Oral Presenter at 9th International Seminar of Magnetic Materials (SMM), 2015 *Awardee*, Karya Salemba Empat Foundation (KSE) Scholarship, 2014-2015

EXTRA-

Chairman of the Faculty Student Council, Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Head of Religious Division Physics' Student Organization, Jan 2014 - Jan 2015 Attended several prestigious leadership summits: LKMM-UI, PGN, Indofood

**PUBLICATIONS** 

Theoretical exploration of optical response of  $Fe_3O_4$ -reduced graphene oxide nano-

particle system within dynamical mean-field theory

(with MA Majidi, AD Fauzi, WY Phan, A Taufik, R Saleh, and A Rusydi) IOP Conference Series: Materials Science and Engineering, Volume 188, 2017

WORKING PAPER Does Traffic Management Matter? Evaluating Congestion Effect of Odd-Even Pol-

icy in Jakarta
[Under Revision]

POLICY REPORT

AND

(with M. Halley Yudhistira and M.F. Hidayat)

*The Sky in Blues: On the recent development of Indonesian airlines industry* (with C. Nuryakin, N. Massie, A. Lumbanraja, S. Hambali, and D. Anindita)

**SOFT** 

Program/Software: Stata, R, Python, LATEX

**SKILLS** 

Languages: Bahasa Indonesia (C2/Native), English (C1), Arabic (A2), Dutch (A2)

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Cycling, Learning new language, and Reading

REFERENCES

Dr. Sabien Dobbelaere

Associate Professor of Economics

DEPARTMENT OF ECONOMICS, VRIJE UNIVERSITEIT AMSTERDAM

Research Fellow, Tinbergen Institute and IZA  $\,$ 

E: sabien.dobbelaere@vu.nl

Dr. M. Halley Yudhistira

Assistant Professor of Economics - Head of Graduate School of Public Policy

DEPARTMENT OF ECONOMICS, UNIVERSITAS INDONESIA

E: m.halley@ui.ac.id